We're going over how to take measurements to have a custom dress made.
And the next measurement that we're going to go over is the shoulder to waist measurement.
This will help the designer know, or pattern maker, whoever is making your dress, know actually how long your torso is.
Some people are a little bit longer torso than others; some are a little bit shorter.
What you want to do is go a head and mark with a, you can mark it with a string or some pins exactly where you take the waist measurement from, which is the narrowest point of your body.
Just go a head and make sure that you have marked evenly.
The next, this will head you being able to take shoulder to waist measurement.
Now you will go from the top of the shoulder at an angle to the center of the waist measurement or the center of the waist.
Now this will give you the proper measurement.
Sometimes seamstresses will ask for shoulder to belly button.
This helps when, if you're not exactly certain where the most narrowest part of your waist is.
Going from shoulder to belly button will also help.